Sopariwala Mohammad Faizan

♥ Vadodara, Gujarat, India ■ mo.faizansopariwala2901@gmail.com □ 9727679753 m https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-faizan-sopariwala-161337217 ♣ https://faizan2901.github.io/drum-kit/contact.html

SUMMARY

Researched technological improvements currently dominating the field, and tested their outcome for specific products. Analysis daily reports and organized data presentations for accountability and quality assurance. Tested the efficacy and safety of products and analyzed the results in relation to procedures.

EXPERIENCE

Research Engineer

AGS Health

July 2022 - Present, Ahemdabad, Gujarat, India

- Understand company software architecture like pipeline of different phases such as Pre-Process, NLP, and code suggestion of Healthcare
- document from initial phase OCR to code suggestion module
- Develop different funtionality java classes which can be useful for suggestion of CPT (Current Procedure Terminology) code
- Improved efficiency of company product CAC(Computer Assisted Coding)
- Learn advanced Java concept like Collections, Spring boot framework and also learn advanced SQL concept like Joins, group by, having
- Learn python for developing analytics skill which is useful for calculate the accuracy of company product like finding statistics for improve
- · efficiancy of product
- Learn different phase of CI/CD integration such as Intergration,QA,Staging, and Production
- Learn how to use Amazon EC2 and S3 for deployment of application on server
- Undertand how our company uses NoSQL such as Graph Database Neo4j which is useful for suggestion of CPT code, learn how neo4j work,
- use of CUI (Context Unique Identifier)
- In Neo4j we have CPT code as Node and CUI as different path for suggesting code

Summer Intern

Gurukula, Tntra Ecosystem

June 2022 - July 2022, Vadodara, Gujarat, India

- Learn clean architecture of Spring boot components like MVC and Django MVT, Git and GitHub
- Learn Development tool Maven

PROJECTS

Food Hub Application

Personal Project • https://github.com/Faizan2901/FoodHub • July 2023 -August 2023

- Develop Food Hub application using advanced Java framework Spring Boot by applying various concept such as Spring Security for security
- purpose like Registration and Login module
- Spring MVC for Model Controller based web application
- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Use} \ \mathsf{Thymleaf} \ \mathsf{template} \ \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{Basic} \ \mathsf{HTML}\text{,} \mathsf{CSS}\text{,} \mathsf{JavaScript} \ \mathsf{for} \ \mathsf{Frontend} \ \mathsf{side} \ \mathsf{development}$
- Functionality: Login, Registration, Place an order of food, Show total bill, also develop Admin side panel
- In this project, I have learn how to run Java based project on AWS EC2 instance, in which gain knowledge regarding AWS services like S3 for cloud storage and EC2 for running project and RDS MySQL of AWS
- Perform CRUD operation on live Database which is RDS MySQL

WeatherAPI

Personal Project • https://github.com/Faizan2901/WhetherAPI • August 2023 -September 2023

- Learn how to call REST API from opensource data
- Implement HTTP respose for getting JSON data
- How to store JSON data in bean object
- Show JSON particular data in UI using Spring boot support Thymleaf
- In this project, I have learn how to run Java based project on AWS EC2 instance, in which gain knowledge regarding AWS services like S3 for cloud storage and EC2 for running project

Kinder Garden Website - Management Site

Personal Project • https://github.com/Faizan2901/NMPC • August 2023 - August 2023

- Implement kinder garden web application using Spring boot framework and different componets of Spring like Security, MVC, REST API
- Funtionality:- Kinder garden Explore page, services, login module, admission process module, attendance module
- Develop admin side and teacher side panel for taking attendance of student
- Develop student side panel for checking their attendance statistics

SKILLS

Java

Spring Boot Framework

Hibernate

Amazon EC2

Amazon S3

SQL

Git & GitHub & E-Git

Data Structure

Problem Solving

5 Rank Hackerrank(Java)

Basic of Python

Basic of HTML, CSS, JavaScript

CERTIFICATIONS

Java (Basic)

Hackerrank Coding Platform • 2022

Certificate in knowledge of programming language - Java

EDUCATION

B.Tech | Computer Engineering

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute of Technology, Vasad | Gujarat Technological University • Vasad - Aanand, Gujarat, India • 2023 • 8.95

Higher School Certificate

Vadodara, Gujarat, India • M.E.S Science Concept School • 2019 • 76.76%

Secondary School Certificate

Sayaji Boys High School • Vadodara, Gujarat, India • 2017 • 78.83%

COURSEWORK

Spring 6 and Spring Boot 3

Udemy • 2023 • Java, Spring Boot, Thymleaf

I have learnt Spring boot with JPA and Spring Security, Spring REST, Spring MVC with in hand project.

Java Programming Language

Udemy • 2022 • Java

I have learnt about Java architecture like JRE, JVM, JDK and Object oriented programming concept.